Just talk to your terminal — in plain language.
And Fusion 360 starts moving on its own.
Today we'll build a robot arm by chatting with GitHub Copilot CLI plus an MCP server.
Build a robot arm — with words.
The setup is simple.
Copilot CLI turns my words into Fusion 360 API calls through the MCP server.
Launch Copilot CLI, and we're ready. Let's start building.
First, the base. A cylinder, 6 cm radius, 2 cm tall.
Done. It even named the body "Base" for us.
Next, a yaw-axis cylinder on top of the base.
Stacked at the right spot in one shot.
Now the upper arm — a box, with fillets in the same prompt.
Even fine details work in plain language.
The elbow pivot is a cylinder along the Y axis.
Axis directions are understood without code.
Forearm — another box, on top of the elbow.
It's starting to look like a real arm.
Last, a two-finger gripper.
Six prompts — and a full robot arm is assembled.
Geometry alone is boring. Let's add joints.
Revolute joints on the yaw axis and the elbow.
And it moves — just like a real robot.
Finally, export to F3D and STL — ready for printing or any other CAD.
Natural language → CAD.
That's what Copilot CLI plus MCP can do.